Stubborn older subordinate
(Questioner) Nice to meet you, Sunim.
(Questioner) I have been working for 25 years.
Now, I am a team leader.
I changed my job 9 years ago.
But I came to a hospital that has
a lot of financial problems.
I brought along a subordinate
who is 2 years older than I am.
I tried to transfer her to another area
but I was opposed by the labor union.
Lately, the workload is increasing.
So, she needs to learn new things.
But she is rather stubborn
and not able to accept changes.
I discussed with my superior
to have her transferred.
But she absolutely refuses
to be transferred.
Although I am able to deal with this,
but for the sake of our team,
I need to get her transferred. But
on a human level, I feel should keep her.
I have been patient with her for the last
9 years, so I might just continue,
or I should get her transferred for
the sake of the team.
This is my dilemma that
I wanted to ask you about.
(Sunim) There is a simpler solution.
No worries.
The easiest thing is for you
to quit your job.
(Questioner and Audience Laughter)
(Questioner) I have actually turned in
a letter of resignation.
(Questioner) But the director said that
(Questioner) I am indispensable
for the work required at the hospital.
(Questioner) So, they have put it on hold.
It doesn't matter that it's put on hold.
Just don't go to work the following day.
(Questioner Laughter)
No need to talk about the hold.
This reminds me of the congressmen submitting
resignation to the speaker of the house.
(Questioner Laughter)
They claim that the speaker has not
approved the letters so they stay on.
You have read it in the papers, no?
Just quit.
(Questioner) Sunim,
it's not a problem for me to quit,
(Questioner) but the other workers are so
stressed and not able to work because of her.
Someone else will take over
and take care of the problem.
(Laughter)
No need to worry.
(Questioner) So, resignation is
the right thing for me to do?
No, I said it's the easiest thing to do.
Not the right thing but the easiest thing.
Since you're having such a difficulty,
it's the easiest thing.
I have already attempted
the easiest solution.
But since my choice is not amenable,
do I go on dealing with her?
Or do I strain to get her transferred?
I told you that the easiest thing
is for you to resign.
Don't give yourself a headache.
You can't quit because they don't let you
or frankly you don't want to quit?
(Questioner) They don't let me quit.
You can resign right now?
(Questioner) Yes, I can.
If they accept your resignation,
you don't have to go to work now?
(Questioner) Yes.
Then, don't go to work starting tomorrow.
(Questioner Laughter)
We need to get clear about this first
in order to discuss further.
I ask you again. Do you really want to
quit but they won't let you?
Or do you want to keep your job
and resolve this problem?
(Questioner) I have endured till now, so
I want to keep working and solve the problem.
So, you're staying
but saying that you don't want to.
Are you being forced to stay
or are you staying because you want to?
(Questioner) It seems that I want to stay.
Right, let's get clear about that first.
You're staying because you want to, right?
The point here is that you are staying,
because of your own need,
not for anyone else's sake.
(Questioner) I have thought
a lot about that also.
(Questioner) I know that I have continued
to work because of my own need
(Questioner) I thought I accepted this fact,
but when I see her, I get all worked up.
But even though you get angry, you have opted
to stay on because of your own need, right?
You still have more to gain by working
in spite of it all, no?
Yes, thank you.
(Laugher and Applause)
(Sunim) I think you got the point
but maybe others have not.
(Questioner Laugher)
You need to see this clearly.
In order to have this benefit,
you need to endure this much.
This is how you can obtain the benefit.
Without this much endurance,
you are not able to attain anything.
You want easy work
but want all the benefits.
Your job includes
this work of managing others well.
Your salary includes this work.
The director said to keep her
when you asked for her transfer.
What could that mean?
He is letting you handle it, no?
(Questioner)
The director approved the transfer.
(Questioner) But the employee refused.
But you just can't stand her.
Get her transferred then. That's easy.
But, after this one is transferred, you think,
it's over?
Yet another person like her
might appear, no?
I think I can handle much better
if one is younger than I am.
(Sunim) Yes, but isn't it possible to
have this occur again?
Yes, it's possible.
(Sunim) Yes, then, you have to get them
transferred again.
If you keep transferring them, you will be
evaluated as not managing them right.
If you can keep an employee
even the director thinks should to be transferred,
you will be regarded as a skillful team leader.
So, as an experiment, you can make the effort
to have her get along better with others.
(Questioner) I have been doing that for 9 years.
(Questioner) In 9 years, nobody has been
transferred out of my department.
(Questioner) But I have endured this
for 9 years, now I am reaching the limit.
Then, why didn't you just transferred her
without asking me?
(Sunim) Why ask me about her transfer?
(Laugher and Applause)
You're either looking for some other way,
Or you want me to share the blame
after the transfer.
Must be one of these two.
Which one is it?
(Questioner) I don't know if I should continue to get
blamed or act tough as I did 9 years ago..
(Questioner) She is a single.
A single in her 50's.
I feel sorry for her sometimes.
At times, I feel that I should just
get her transferred
I think I am in between positions.
(Questioner) I decided to ask you
because I can't decide.
You feel sorry for her.
Show a little more compassion for her.
(Questioner Laugher)
I see.
(Applause)
There are always a few people like this.
The company can run more smoothly
without such people.
But if such people can be accepted,
you become more tolerant
and the company will benefit.
If you keep getting rid of
such people one after another,
it might be better in the short run,
but eventually, you will keep having issues
with all kinds of people in the world.
It's like those pop up gopher games
you see on the streets.
You bop this and that pops up.
You bop that and this one pops up. Seen it?
You know the game, right?
Life is just like that.
You get rid of this problem,
then that pops up.
You beat that one down,
then this one pops up.
Like when you finally solve the big
problem with your husband,
then a problem with your children arises.
After solving this one,
a money problem arises.
When the money problem is solved,
a problem with the parents come.
Life's problems are ongoing.
If we wish that we should have no problem,
we will continue to live
a life of suffering.
So, you need to know and accept that
problems arise all the time in life.
There will be rainy days, sunny days,
cold day, and hot days.
So then what is the true freedom
from all this?
Instead of wishing for calm weather,
use an umbrella when it rains.
If it's cold, put on another layer.
If it's hot, take off a layer.
Having this attitude of coping
with whatever arises.
This is freedom and is liberation.
We don't become free by changing
what is out there.
Real freedom is having the ability
to cope with whatever is out there.
(Applause)
So, the easiest choice is to quit your job.
Second is to get rid of her.
The third, the hardest is to keep her.
These are your choices, right?
Do you want to take the easy route
or try to solve the difficulty?
Let go of 9 years of effort by getting rid of her?
Or, having endured for 9 years,
make some more effort to succeed?
What do you think?
(Questioner) She says she can't find
another job elsewhere. And she is single.
(Questioner) Sunim, I drank for 3 days
till yesterday to relieve the stress.
But I do feel sorry for her; she is single.
I think I should keep her.
(Applause)
Do you know why I recommend that?
By asking me,
you wanted to find a solution.
You didn't just want to get rid of her.
You wanted a solution.
That is why I say this.
You still want to find a solution.
You have to realize that the same ways of
the last 9 years will not work.
You can't just hold it in.
You need to flip the problem over.
Every morning,
Do 108 prostrations and pray for her.
"How hard it must be living by yourself."
How would you feel
if she were your sibling?
You have to pray for her.
Then, a solution will be revealed to you.